FARID BEKRAN

Software engineer





TECHNICAL SKILLS

C# | .NET 6.0 | ASP.NET Core | EF Core | TypeScript | SQL Server | Redis | RabbitMQ | Angular | Scrum | Kanban | 00P | SOLID | Unit testing

SOFT SKILLS

Patience | Adaptability | Critical thinking | Accountability | Time and project management

WHO AM I?

With over 10 years of experience, I am a software engineer with a established history of working in the software development and financial data processing industry. Skilled in C#, Scrum, Web Applications, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Performance testing, Unit testing and SOLID principles. Have strong knowledge of financial and stock exchange software. Maybe I am among a few software engineers who love working as a catalyst between business people and technical people. I also like to work with legacy code to use my knowledge in refactoring and clean code along with delivering business value to stackholders of the software.

EXPERIENCE

9/2020 - present

Senior Software engineer

Mabna DP (Iran)

I have worked in the OMS software team as a backend developer. In that period I've managed to implement complex treasury logic for continuously in-use OMS software and replace it with the previous troublesome module. I have developed an in-house broker back-office module for the OMS software that lets the OMS work independently from existing back-office software in the market. I am currently in charge of another project in the company that focuses on portfolio management features. This software needs to be changed to make it available for much bigger customers, which is one of my goals in the new team. Making the team more efficient, reliable, and happy is another goal of mine in the new team. I believe I've had good progress in both goals because of my technical and interpersonal skills.

2016 - 2020 Full-Time

Senior Software Engineer

Fanap Plus (Iran)

In charge of some web softwares and a data integration project called DataLake implementing some patterns of industry established DataLake definition. This tool is developed by Microsoft technologies and the main storage engine is Microsoft Sql Server and there are some Feeder (I have coined the term) which are responsible for data ingestion.

2018 - 2019 Part-Time

Technical Consultant

elwin.ir (Iran)

In the company's main product the Online customer satisfaction measurement I have helped the team both technically and non-technically to deliver high quality software which is responsible for serving backend for physical kiosks and a comprehensive solution of reporting based on their specific requirements.

2016 - 2018

Part-Time

Software developer

Afranet (Iran)

I have played a key role on delivery of BSS/OSS software in Afranet which the company was developing in-house. One of my main achievements during that project was a successful effort of a balancing business owners needs and the development team through collaborating with business analysts and development team. I personally was in charge of development of invoicing module of that software system.

2014 - 2016 Full-Time Software developer

Nomatec (Iran)

2012 - 2014

Full-Time

Software developer

System Group (Iran)

EDUCATION

2007 - 2010

Bachelor's Degree Computer Science University of Tabriz Iran

HOBBIES

∞ Creating Podcast

pod.link/1596644229

I am in charge of podcast's technical aspects like recording and distributing episodes.

 ∞ Amateur Photography

unsplash.com/@faridbekran

LANGUAGES

English - Working proficiency Turkish - proficient Persian, Azerbaijani - native